# MANSI THAKKAR

## • DETAILS •

Union City, NJ, 07087 United States +1 (872) 279 4513 mansi.thakkar1095@gmail.com

LINKSLinkedIn

## ° STRENGTH °

Fast Learner

Teambuilding

**Interpersonal Communication** 

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Leadership

Work Efficiently with Deadlines

Adaptability

Ability to Negotiate

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

AutoCAD Revit Sketch-up Photoshop

Project Management Tools:
Procore
Microsoft Project Professional
Bluebeam
Microsoft Excel
Microsoft Office Suite

# CERTIFICATIONS

OSHA 30HR

Licensed Architect - COA India

Foundations of Project Management Course -Google

### PROFILE

As an Assistant Project Manager, I have gained extensive experience in coordinating construction and architectural projects. I have worked closely with contractors, architects, and engineers to ensure that projects are executed in accordance with project specifications and requirements. I have also demonstrated organizational and problem-solving skills, effectively managing competing priorities and resolving project issues in a timely and efficient manner. i am Enthusiastic to be utilized to the best of my ability and trained at the top of the management.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

Intern - Assistant Project Manager at Ramani Group -VVR Developers LLC, Roselle Park, NJ

January 2023 — Present

- Coordinating with Project Manager and reporting to the Senior Director of Residential Project Management.
- Assisting the Project manager in creating and managing Change orders, purchase orders and subcontract agreements
- Preparing baseline schedule and two week look ahead
- Coordinate the preparation of RFIs and submittals from construction vendors and subcontractors in order to determine the products and services that are available to meet project standards.
- Conducted shop drawing reviews to ensure that all products and materials met project specifications.
- Review and communicate with the owner and engineers about ongoing projects' plans and specifications.

Project Manager & Architect at Studio Imagine-Interiors and Architects, Gujarat, India November 2019 — May 2021

- Designed and managed architectural and working detailed drawings for multi-family and commercial government projects.
- Lead the team of four for a residential project approximately of 62,000 sq. ft. starting from conceptual level till final construction.
- Collaborated with builders to confirm construction drawings and designs.
- Reviewed and monitored contractors' schedules and submission of shop drawings and samples.
- Conducted construction site visits to monitor plan compliance.
- Interacted with clients to provide timely and relevant status updates.

## Intern Architect at Design Studio, Gujarat, India

June 2017 — October 2017

- Prepared building specifications based on local regulations and codes.
- Maintained and organized blueprint files.
- Worked closely with a multi-disciplinary team to design a high-rise project.

# EDUCATION

Master of Science, Construction Engineering & Management, Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, New Jersey

January 2022 — May 2023

**Coursework:** Project Management, Safety Management, Cost analysis & estimating, Scheduling, Temporary Structures & Problems in Heavy Construction.

Bachelor of Architecture, ITM School of Architecture Art and Design, Gujarat, India August 2014 — May 2019